let's look at the solution to our unlock
quiz where we were asked really what
does unlock do
does it just store zero to lockvar
does it check whether the lockvar is one
and then do a store conditional
atomically to make it zero or do we need
additional atomic instructions that are
gonna somehow
unlock the lock and the answer is that
unlike the lock function where we needed
to both
check whether the lock is available and
make it busy in one go
the unlock function
is done only by the thread that actually
has the lock
so when we get to unlock we know that
the lock is busy because we made it busy
all we have to do is just
make the log free we can do that by
writing zero in any way we want so we
choose the simplest way of just doing a
normal store to the lock variable
so we don't need to atomically test
whether it's one and then make it 0 and
we definitely don't need additional
atomic instructions